[poignant music playing]
[exhales]
[Do] Oh.
[unbuckles seat belt]
Mrs. Oh!
- Are you all right?
- [groans weakly]
It's absolutely freezing out here today.
Do you think you can stand?
- Yeah.
- Let's go.
- I'm gonna take you home right now.
- Oh goodness, thank you so much.
[Kyeong-suk groans]
[poignant music continues]
I'll grab that.
There we go.
I'm sorry.
I guess now… I owe you another one.
Don't forget to keep the promise you made.
You said
you would take a break every hour.
I know.
I try to do that, except it's not easy.
I have to keep fighting for my son,
so that other--
So that other people's
precious children are safe.
Because nothing will ever change
in this world
unless you do something about it.
Right, Mrs. Oh?
I get it, I do. Except,
your health should be
your first priority, okay?
Goodness, Officer Lee.
[poignant music continues]
Thank you for your kind words.
You might be the only person
in the world who cares about me.
[chuckles] I'm just doing my job.
Go inside and rest up.
All right.
Oh, hold on. Just wait a minute.
Just wait a moment. I'll be right back.
Huh.
[chuckles softly]
- This is some kimchi that I just made.
- Oh.
And it turned out really nicely. Take it!
That's all right, Mrs. Oh.
I've got plenty of food at home.
Come on, you said that you love
my homemade side dishes.
- Mrs. Oh, that's really sweet, but--
- Please.
It's just,
when I see you, I think of my son,
and it's… Please just take it.
- [poignant music continues]
- [Kyeong-suk laughs]
[Do] Thank you.
Get some rest.
[poignant music continues]
[gun clicks, fires]
[gunshot echoes]
- [music fades]
- [Do] We're almost there, Mrs. Oh.
Can you hear me? It's all gonna be okay,
but you need to stay awake.
OPERATION ROOM
Authorized personnel only.
I'm afraid I'm gonna have to ask you
to wait outside.
She'll be okay, right?
[exhales forcefully]
[uneasy music playing]
SURGERY IN PROGRESS
Where are you going?
Hey! Tell me where you're going!
[tense music playing]
That cop you hate just barged in.
[man 1] What the hell?
The pig is back.
[sighs]
I warned you, didn't I?
Hey. Have you finally lost
your fucking mind or what?
Where's Gong Seok-ho?
[thumping, clattering]
[men screaming, grunting]
[thumping, clattering continues]
[men continue screaming, grunting]
[music fades]
- [indistinct chatter]
- [patients groaning, moaning]
[man] I said it fucking hurts, god dammit!
- What's going on here?
- [phone buzzing]
LEE DO
[patient groaning]
[Seo] Do, where are you?
What the hell's going on here?
Pat down all the guys there.
See if anyone's got a list of addresses.
Addresses?
Guys, search all these lowlifes' pockets.
Hey, hold him down.
Hold me down?
What the fuck do you mean, man?
Stay still, shithead.
Fuck you, asshole!
Don't touch me. Fuck off!
[screams]
Ah, you fucking assholes!
Fuck! Ugh, damn it! [sobs]
ORDER ADDRESS LIST
[Seo] What's this?
[Seo] Do!
Did you check the vehicle
parked in that alley?
There aren't
any security cameras over there,
so I wanted to see if any of the cameras
around here caught anything.
And the list?
What exactly is this address list?
[indistinct chatter]
Compare these.
- [Do sighs]
- "5 Domyeong-ro, 1-gil."
Hey, that's Mrs. Oh.
- [mysterious music playing]
- What is this?
This is the same address as hers.
That's right.
I don't think all these recent shootings
have been happening randomly.
What do you mean?
It's been orchestrated.
The guns were
couriered to all these people,
so that means
that there's someone out there
who's hoping
these desperate people will use the guns.
[Seo] All of the suspects
in these shootings
have been ordinary citizens.
None of them have
sufficient wealth or jobs
that give them easy access to guns
or any kind of illegal smuggling.
I believe that these guns
were sent to them
through an individual or group
hoping to take advantage
of their desperate circumstances
and their potential to pull the trigger.
This list of addresses is the proof.
So you're saying each box contained a gun
and a list of addresses.
[mysterious music continues]
Why would they put these lists
in the boxes?
To expose each gun recipient
to each other,
right down to their addresses,
which would accelerate their anxiety.
[Seo] Yes, the list shows
each gun recipient
where they can find other guns,
but also exposes all the other people
who've gotten them too.
Yu Jeong-tae, the gosiwon shooter,
mentioned it, remember?
[Jeong-tae] There are…
more guns out there.
There are more people out there with guns.
A recipient could come to your house
looking for a gun,
and then if you decide you need more guns…
You can go find them yourself.
That's right. Jo U-tae saw this list
and came here looking for a gun.
[U-tae] Evening, ma'am.
Tell me where the gun is.
And they're not just giving out the guns.
They're probably surveilling everyone.
Watching what each of them
will do with the guns.
So do we have information
about the names on this list?
[Seo] Look at this.
When they first set up an account
for their cell, they create a username.
I'm fairly certain those are the names.
But this is personal information.
How could they get their hands on
something like that?
They probably installed malware
on each cell phone
when the account was set up.
Yes, that's right.
We found malware set on all the phones
belonging to Yu Jeong-tae,
Jeon Won-seong, and Oh Kyeong-suk.
It kept track of everything,
including call history,
text messages,
and all personal information.
Hang on a second. Didn't everyone say
that the packages were delivered
but there were no records?
That's why I think that they deliberately
disguised them as packages.
Having packages couriered is
part of everyday life for Koreans,
and we don't notice
or interfere with other people's things.
My God,
who the hell is behind all this bullshit?
And what is it all for?
If this is all true,
then we've got a huge problem.
Let's start with checking the facts first.
You'll have to figure out the legal names
of the people on this list
and match them with each address.
And more importantly,
you have to check if they have any guns,
and if they do,
you'll confiscate them all.
[all] Yes, sir
Detective Seo.
Yes?
Lee Do was the one who found all this out?
Yes, sir. Officer Lee found it out,
as well as the Oh Kyeong-suk incident.
Tell him to be careful not to get into
any more trouble, since he's suspended.
Yes, sir.
However, it's also thanks to him
that we got this lead,
so we'll have to work harder.
- [Seo] Yes, sir.
- Get what I'm saying?
Yes, I understand.
- And tell him nice work.
- Yes, sir.
[phone buzzing]
Officer Lee?
Are you free to talk right now?
- Yes, go ahead.
- [inhales sharply]
It's about Moon Baek.
I went ahead and did some digging,
and… Dongwol Industries is
a state-authorized arms distributor
that exports weapons for military use.
So they've got very strict security,
and informed me they would
only respond to an official letter,
so I looked for some basic information.
[inhales sharply]
Moon Baek had been working at the company
and quit right at the end of last year.
And the reason that he gave
was that he had terminal cancer.
Apparently, he was very popular
with his coworkers too.
Oh, really?
By the way, sir,
how did you even end up
getting involved with that guy?
Ah, well,
that's a long story,
so let's keep it quiet for now.
Oh, okay. No problem, Officer Lee.
[groaning]
Hey!
Where the hell did you go, huh?
You're not supposed to just take off
like that!
- Have you been here this whole time?
- Of course I have. Can't you tell?
[Moon Baek sighs]
None of this concerns you,
so why stick around?
Well, this is
a new side of you.
You know, a "thank you" might be nice,
if it's not too much trouble.
[sighs wearily]
I just can't figure you out.
[Do sighs wearily]
[Do] I should've called her back.
What did…
what did Mrs. Oh say earlier?
[Moon Baek] Hmm?
In the car, earlier.
Wow.
You picked up on that conversation,
even with all the chaos?
She said,
"At least now I'll die
without any regrets,
so there's no need
for you to go to all this trouble for me."
[gentle music playing]
By the way,
why is she "Mother" in your phone
if she isn't your real mom?
Because…
because she treats me like a son.
Oh, right.
Wouldn't your real mom be hurt
if she heard you say that?
She died when I was young.
- [sirens wailing]
- [officer 1] Stay still! Stay still!
[officer 2] You are under arrest
for murder!
[officer 2] You have
the right to an attorney!
If you cannot afford an attorney…
Sorry.
I asked because I was curious,
since I don't have a mom either.
[gentle music continues]
You lost your mom too?
I have no idea
whether she's dead or alive.
The only thing I know…
is that, apparently, it snowed a lot…
the day I was abandoned.
- [wind whistling]
- [baby cries]
PLEASE WRITE DOWN THE CHILD'S NAME
AND DATE OF BIRTH
[gentle music continues]
[woman 1] Excuse me.
Were you going to leave it there?
Then you might as well hand him over.
I'm the one
who collects the babies from there.
[woman 2] Well…
Don't worry.
It's okay, really.
It's so cold.
You shouldn't leave him there anyway.
Does the baby have a name?
A name?
Before she abandoned me,
did she even give me a name?
[baby Moon Baek cries]
[gentle music continues]
[music turns unsettling]
[man] Is it a boy or a girl?
No idea. Let's go before someone sees.
Well, hope it's a boy.
They're worth a hell of a lot more.
[music fades]
[upbeat pop music playing on stereo]
FAMILY MILK DISTRIBUTION CENTER
[man 1] Listen, if you're gonna buy one,
then why not just buy both?
I mean, you could take just one eye,
but then how the hell
am I supposed to sell a one-eyed freak?
[man 2] Look, they said
they only needed one.
And they also said they'd pay well.
- What?
- They said they'd pay well!
[music stops]
What do you mean? How much exactly?
Hundred million.
How does that sound to you?
All right,
tell me what kind of blood type they want.
Type AB.
Ah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Hey, hey, pick a fresh one, okay?
- Yeah, of course I will.
All right,
let's hurry up and get this door open now!
We're gonna make some money!
Type AB…
Let's see, let's see…
Hey!
Yeah, you. Come over here.
Yeah.
[man 1 singing a happy tune]
What are we gonna drink tonight? Soju?
Oh, no.
How about beer? Not beer either!
Hard liquor, hard liquor!
We're gonna have some hard liquor!
Let's drink that hard liquor,
yeah, yeah, yeah!
- [man 1 sighs]
- [somber music playing]
Good job. You got to keep one.
[laughs]
Hey! Let's go get some hard liquor!
[man 1 singing a happy tune]
[Moon Baek] At that moment,
I had a feeling
that my life probably wasn't going to be
a walk in the park.
And it turns out that feeling…
became my reality.
[indistinct announcement over PA]
After I got sent back several times,
by a few different families,
they sent me somewhere really far away.
[woman sighs]
- Mommy?
- What?
Tell me why it's good
that I'm going to the US.
Anywhere else is better than here.
Because of your eye,
if you stay here,
you'll just end up in the gutter.
The US is the land of opportunity,
you know.
So try hard to make a life
for yourself there.
And if you wanna be loved,
always keep a smile on your face.
[somber music continues]
One more thing.
I'm not your mom, so stop calling me that.
It bothers me.
If you wanna be loved, always smile.
What a shitty thing to say to me.
[dramatic music playing]
- She said it was the land of opportunity…
- [door closes]
- [child wails]
- [man 3] Hey, sit down!
[Moon Baek] …but it was way worse
than any gutter. It was hell.
[man 4] What do you wanna
get started with?
Anything with a good price.
Okay.
[agent 1] Freeze! FBI!
Put your gun down!
[rapid gunfire]
[agent 2] You, check over there.
- [agent 3] Check upstairs!
- [agent 1] Shit.
This kid's still alive.
We need an ambulance here!
[music fades]
[inhales deeply]
Unfortunately, I've got a great memory,
so all that pain is still pretty raw.
Now, don't pity me too much.
Thanks for today.
You should get some rest.
That's okay.
I may not have much time left,
but what I do have is loyalty.
I'll wait here with you.
[Moon Baek groans sleepily]
[indistinct chatter]
[Seong-jun] Fuck-gyu.
Fuck-gyu…
Don't ignore me, you little shit.
You better be waiting
at the karaoke later.
[Seong-jun grunts]
[Seong-jun sighs]
Why should I?
What?
[sighs] Why is this fucker
acting up again?
I just don't wanna go.
Say that to me again.
Huh?
- Don't wanna go?
- No.
You listen to me, asshole.
Want me to leak
those spycam pics you took?
- [boy 1] Seong-jun…
- [man] Hey, you punks! Get to class!
- [electronic melody playing over PA]
- Why aren't you two going in?
The bell rang. Get to class.
[teacher 1 exhales sharply] Little punks…
- [Seong-jun] Hey. Get lost.
- [boy 2] Okay.
[Seong-jun] Hey.
Tell me that again.
- You don't wanna?
- [Seong-jun kicks chair]
You don't wanna?
Answer me, you stupid bitch.
Okay.
Stop it.
- [scoffs]
- [door opens]
[door closes]
Hello there, guys.
[students] Hello.
So what page are we on today?
Stop it?
[teacher 2] We're looking at…
Hey. Since when do you think
you have a choice?
You serve me.
and you should do as you're told.
[inhales deeply]
[menacing music playing]
Call her "math whore."
- No.
- Go on. Do it.
Do it.
Do it!
I said do it, you motherfucker!
- Do it.
- [fabric tears]
- [music builds]
[music fades]
- What the hell?
- [teacher 2] Park Gyu-jin.
- [exhales deeply]
- What is it? What's the matter?
[Gyu-jin] Hey, asshole.
Stop it.
Just stop when I tell you to stop.
I told you to stop it, didn't I?
Just stop it. Stop it! Stop it!
- [unsettling music playing]
- Fucking stop, you motherfucker! Stop!
Stop it! Stop, you fucking jerk-off!
Stop! Stop!
[music fades]
Fucking shit!
Officer Lee is such a motherfucker.
What do you think this is about?
That's what I've been wondering.
Who the hell is this fucker,
and why's that cop on my ass about him?
[uneasy music playing]
This is…
What? Do you know this guy?
He's one of Gu Jeong-man's guys.
What?
You sure about that?
The day we took care of Mr. Kim,
that guy was standing right behind him.
That's why I recognize him.
No! This is wrong, you fucking animals!
Damn you! I curse you, you son of a bitch!
- [Kim screaming, yelling]
- Come on!
[uneasy music continues]
[exhales sharply]
Gu Jeong-man. That shitstain…
[Se-yeong] Dad, do you think
you could help me out a little bit?
Hmm? Why?
Are you in trouble? What happened now?
[Se-yeong] Could I borrow
some money from you?
[Cho] Why?
What are you going to use it for?
[Se-yeong] I promise I'll pay you back.
[Jeong-u] What's been going on
with Sergeant Cho lately?
[officer] Someday, when you have kids,
you'll understand.
Hey, look, just play dumb
until he brings it up himself.
Yeah.
[Jeong-u] I was just a bit worried.
[officer] Oh boy.
They really are fighting.
I don't see why
you wanna live in that place.
[man] Are you
Mrs. Oh Kyeong-suk's emergency contact?
First of all, the surgery went very well,
so there's no need to worry about that.
Could you and I talk for a moment?
[monitor beeping]
During the procedure, we noticed
an infection in her internal organs.
After the surgery, we decided to place her
in a negative-pressure isolation room.
But, given her test results…
[whispering] Thank you so much,
Oh Kyeong-suk.
[doctor] We'll need to monitor
the infection for a few days.
[woman on TV] Earlier this afternoon,
an incident occurred in the subway
when a peddler selling toy guns
frightened passengers on the train.
While trying to flee,
a mad crush resulted in many injuries
as people fell on each other.
Due to the series of recent shootings
all over the city,
passengers mistook the toy guns
for real weapons,
resulting in mass chaos
inside the subway train.
Funny how the world can change
in an instant, isn't it?
[Do] Mm.
That's how scary guns are.
Scary?
Mm-hmm.
Guns are scary.
[pensive music playing]
A long time ago,
there was a very peaceful village.
And then one day, a man left a gun
at the town square and vanished.
And then pretty soon,
that gun disappeared,
and the town began to change drastically.
As more and more people
were getting shot and killed,
the villagers got
more and more suspicious of each other,
and they all lined up,
because they wanted to buy their own guns.
And the man who was watching it all…
smiled with satisfaction.
[pensive music continues]
Why do you think that he smiled?
Well, maybe things turned out
the way he wanted.
He made people believe
that guns equal justice,
so they would rely on their power.
- But what about all those people?
- Hmm?
All the people who are getting those guns.
Maybe to all of them,
a gun actually could equal justice
and power.
A gun doesn't offer justice.
It doesn't offer power.
Guns only bring you self-destruction.
[music fades]
That's why I think
you should stop looking for them too.
If you don't have that much time,
shouldn't you spend it on yourself?
[exhales]
By the way, who was that guy?
The man who left the first gun.
An Asian man with blue eyes.
Least that's what I heard.
[distant siren wailing]
- [Jeong-man] All of them are in here?
- Yeah, I made sure to check.
Jeong-man! Hey! You guys wait here.
Ah, damn it!
[bell chimes]
[indistinct announcement echoing faintly]
[man] Shit! When did they all get here?
Damn it.
Did they say how U-tae was?
Uh, according to the nurses…
[sighs] …he might end up
in a wheelchair forever.
[Jeong-man grunts]
[Jeong-man] Fuck!
[sighs] I told him
not to be so fuckin' rash!
[exhales sharply]
What about that fucker?
The fucking cop who did this to Woo-tae.
Did you find him?
No, not yet. We're still looking for him.
Fuck! We just have to wait
and see what happens.
So there's no chance
of getting better with surgery?
[Moon Baek] I don't wanna do it.
I don't need any more pain in this life.
[exhales]
[sighs deeply] Oh shit…
- [exhales sharply] Fucking son of a bitch.
- [elevator dings]
Are you getting on?
[Jeong-man] Oh.
Oh, sorry.
[tense music playing]
[tense music continues]
[phone buzzing]
Yeah, hi, Officer Jang.
I'm at the hospital. Yeah.
I'm heading down now.
I'll see you downstairs.
No, I don't need anything, thanks.
Yep, got it.
Officer Lee,
wanna grab food before we go?
I'm starving.
Yeah, let's do that.
[phone buzzing]
- Excuse me.
- Yeah?
- Something's buzzing on you.
- [music fades]
I think it's your phone.
[buzzing continues]
Sorry about that.
SEOK-HO
- [Jeong-u] Hello, Officer Lee.
- Oh, you're here.
This is Moon Baek. This is Officer Jang.
Oh! Hello.
- Okay, let's go.
- [Jeong-u] Sure.
See ya!
- You take care, now.
- Okay!
Bye!
[tense music playing]
[engine starts]
[man 1] That was pretty cool.
[Jeong-man] Don't drive too close to them.
It'll be too obvious.
[man 1] Hey, hey!
Mr. Gong is calling again.
[Jeong-man] Fuck, why does this asshole
keep calling me?
[phone buzzing]
- Hey, why the hell isn't he picking up?
- I don't know.
SEOK-HO
Jeong-man, you sure
you should be ignoring him?
[indistinct chatter]
Won't Gong only become
more suspicious of you?
[man 3] No.
He doesn't have to take that call.
- Ah, shit. This is terrible timing.
- [man 2] Yeah, well it's not you.
- [man 1] I'm just saying--
- Hey, you guys, shut up.
[music fades]
- Hello, sir.
- [Seok-ho] Fucking hell!
You don't know how to answer
your phone anymore?
Yeah, I'm sorry about that.
A few of my boys got hurt
on the job tonight.
- God damn it!
- So I've been a little preoccupied.
- Listen.
- Yeah?
Get over here now.
What?
- Right now?
- Yeah that's right, you fucking prick!
Get your ass over here right away.
Understood, sir.
What should we do?
Turn the car around.
Bring them all in.
[man] Yes, sir.
[ominous music playing]
[engine roars]
[menacing music playing]
[music subsides]
[intriguing music playing]
Explain. [sighs]
[man 1] Looks like there's
a power struggle between the factions.
I was reporting to some other guy
before you,
collecting the guns
he was scattering around.
[man 2] Things are more complicated
than we thought.
If anyone catches wind of the operation,
it's over.
We need to report to Jake
and pull out now.
What about the guns? [sighs]
[man 1] They're probably stashed
somewhere in Mr. Kim's club.
But if we're taking over,
getting to them won't be easy.
It's going to take some time
to secure them.
[man 2] Should we revise the plan?
Revise?
For whom?
[man 3] If someone else
messes with Kim's stock…
Sir, things are looking
pretty bad out there.
Bad news is spilling everywhere,
and also, Jake has expressed concern.
Jake? What concern?
Korea is heavily influenced
by public opinion,
and if this rattles the plan,
surveillance and regulations will only--
Hey.
[music turns uneasy]
[inhales deeply]
Of all the choices…
who picked Kim?
I…
Ah, so… if there's a flaw in my plan,
it's you.
[Moon Baek sighs]
Now,
are there any more problems?
[man 1] No, sir.
Just give us the order.
Look for anyone desperate enough
to get their hands on a gun.
I will, sir.
No more mistakes.
[man 1] Yes, sir.
[music fades]
[uneasy music playing]
Boss, the money's good.
- Show them the merchandise.
- Yes, boss.
- [man 2] I'm gonna show you something.
- [man 3] Let's see.
- [man 2] Look at this.
- [man 3] Oh, that's sick, man.
- [man 2] You like it?
- [man 3] Take a look.
[man 2] One shot, one kill.
[man 3] Wow, that's beautiful, man.
[car door opens]
Get your ass ready.
We hit as soon as the deal's done.
Okay. Got it.
Hi.
What the fuck? Fuck!
[suspenseful music playing]
I didn't realize
that this fine pistol was only 250.
Who the hell are you?
It's a little sad…
that you don't remember.
[surgeon]
What do you wanna get started with?
Anything with a good price.
- [man 3] What the fuck is going on?
- [dramatic music playing]
[man 4] Boss!
Looks like there was an ambush.
Dumb motherfuckers!
[man 2] Boss, look.
- [music fades]
- [breathing heavily, coughs]
[ominous music playing]
[boss] Damn, kid.
You do all this yourself?
[breathing heavily]
[music fades]
[groans]
[breathing heavily]
Finally awake.
You know, you've been dead
to the world almost three weeks.
Where am I?
You're home.
This is your home now.
Are you a good guy?
Good, bad… Depends on who you ask.
But I can tell you this.
I'm the best thing
that is ever gonna happen for you.
Why?
I like you.
Yeah, but… why?
You gotta look at it from my perspective.
You see this little kid
with this cheap gun wrapped into his hand
go charging headfirst into the lion's den.
What is not to like?
[groans, inhales deeply]
My head hurts too much.
Yeah, that's… that's a gift.
It's gonna take some getting used to.
A gift?
I hope you like it.
[brooding rock music playing]
[object clatters]
Welcome to the new world,
Blue Brown.
[teenage Baek]
What kind of people are you?
[boss laughs]
[boss] Well, anyone who wants a gun
comes to me.
It's a tough business.
That's why I need tough people.
Like you.
[teenage Baek] You chose the wrong one.
I'm too weak.
You're not the toughest kid on the block.
But with this in your hand,
you'll become a whole different person.
[brooding rock music continues]
From now on,
you determine your own value.
[brooding rock music continues]
[Moon Baek] Bring up the gun locations.
Start getting excited.
Because a new world will soon be here.
[brooding rock music continues]
[music fades]
[funky rock music playing]